JASON RUSHTON

http://JasonRushton.com | jason@jasonrushton.com | 435-680-0190

Overview

Please see http://jasonrushton.com for additional background and project examples.

I'm a full-stack web developer with a deep understanding of every layer of web application architecture, and I absolutely love building stuff on the web. I've been at it since 2000, way back in the days of font tags, web safe colors, and using pixel.gif to make table based layouts work.

As a developer who enjoys front-end work, web development is in an incredibly exciting place. With the rise of client side SPA frameworks like React and Angular, alongside running Node on the server and for tooling, I have great hope for the future of building web based applications.

Skills

Javascript

Frameworks: React.js, Angular.js

Libraries: Immutable.js, Async, Iodash / Underscore, jQuery Page.js

Techniques: ES6, Isomorphic, Single Page Applications

Templating: Jade, React JSX, LoDash, JST

Tools: NPM, Browserify, Babel, Gulp, Grunt, Bower, Misc: API, JSON, AJAX, DOM, Object Oriented

Back-End

Applications: Node.js, ColdFusion Frameworks: Express, Restify

Languages: Javascript, T-SQL, CFML & CFScript Source Control: Git & GitHub, SVN, Kiln / HG Techniques: Isomorphic Javascript, MVC, MVVM

Web Optimization

Optimization: Minification Concatenation, CSS Prefixing, Cache

Busting, CDN Usage

SEO: URL Rewriting, Site Structure, Schema.org, Semantic HTML

Front-End

CSS: CSS3, Less, PostCSS, Bootstrap, Grid Layouts, Responsive

Misc: DOM, HTML5, SVG

Database

Engines: MS SQL, SQLite

Programming: T-SQL, Stored Procedures

Tuning: Indexing, Query Optimization, (De)Normalization

Server Management

Servers: Heroku, Node, Windows, IIS, Coldfusion, MS SQL

Work History

4 years as Owner of The Local Network, 2011 - Current

I've done all site design and development, SEO optimizations, and server management. Most sites involve ongoing automated mass data importation as new data is available. Most of my time has been spent experimenting with new technology and techniques while porting old applications from ColdFusion over to Node.js.

9 years at iWorks Inc. 2001 - 2010

- 1 year as designer, 2 years as developer, 6 years as lead developer

Designed, built, and maintained all back office applications: CRM, Billing, Reporting, Marketing, and API's. I was responsible for the vast majority of the application stack, from the backend codebase, database modeling, front end design and scripting, report generation and automation, along with API creation, documentation and consumption. Assisted and supported server administrators.

Education

Dixie College, 1998 - 2000

Full spectrum of Visual Technology related classes covering HTML, PhotoShop and Illustrator, as well as C++, 3d modeling, ShockWave and print applications